Guide to the Child Study Center, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of Donald J. Cohen as director, 1970-2001; Accession 2002-A-211
  - Chapters written by Dr. Cohen
    - Tourette's Syndrome: A Model Developmental Neuropsychiatric Disorder. In: New Approaches To Mental Health From Birth To Adolescence. Yearbook Of The International Association For Child And Adolescent Psychiatry And Allied Professions, C. Chiland, J.G. Young (Eds.). New Haven And London: Yale University Press, Vol. 9, Chapter (1992) (Box 3)
    - Postmortem Analysis Of Subcortical Monoamines And Amino Acids In Tourette Syndrome. In: Tourette Syndrome: Genetics, Neurobiology and Treatment. T.N. Chase, A.J. Friedhoff and D.J. Cohen (Eds.). New York: Raven Press, Chapter 15 (1992) (Box 3)
    - Neuroendocrine And Behavioral Effects Of Naloxone In Tourette Syndrome. In: Tourette Syndrome: Genetics, Neurobiology and Treatment. T.N. Chase, A.J. Friedhoff and D.J. Cohen (Eds.). New York: Raven Press, Chapter 31 (1992) (Box 3)
    - Tourette Syndrome: Extending Basic Research To Clinical Care. Tourette Syndrome: Genetics, Neurobiology and Treatment. T.N. Chase, A.J. Friedhoff and D.J. Cohen (Eds.). New York: Raven Press, Chapter 41 (1992) (Box 3)
    - The Child And Adolescent With Tourette's Syndrome: Clinical Perspectives On Phenomenology And Treatment. In: Handbook Of Tourette's Syndrome And Related Tic And Behavioral Disorders, R. Kurlan (Ed.). New York: Marcel Dekker, Inc., Chapter 25 (1993) (Box 3)
    - Desire And Fantasy: A Psychoanalytic Perspective On Theory Of Mind And Autism. In: Understanding Other Minds: Perspectives From Autism, S. Baron-Cohen, H. Tager-Flusberg, D.J. Cohen (Eds.). London: Oxford Univ. Press: Chapter 20 (1993) (Box 4)
    - Children And Inner-City Violence: Strategies For Intervention. In: Psychological Effects Of War And Violence On Children, L. Leavitt, N. Fox (Eds.). Lawrence Erlbaum Assoc., Chapter 15 (1993) (Box 4)
    - Tic Disorders. In: Child And Adolescent Psychiatry: Modern Approaches, Third Edition, M. Rutter, E. Taylor, L. Herzov (Eds.). Oxford: Blackwell Scientific Publications, Chapter 26 (1994) (Box 4)
    - Developmental Psychopathology Of Multiplex Developmental Disorder. In: Developmental Follow-Up: Concepts, Genres, Domains And Methods, S.L. Freidman, H.C. Haywood (Eds.). Academic Press (1994) (Box 4)
    - Autism. In: Encyclopedia Of Intelligence, R.J. Sternberg, (Ed.). Mcmillan Publishers, Volume 1 (1994) (Box 4)
    - Tics And Tourette's Syndrome. In: Behavioral And Developmental Pediatrics: A Handbook For Primary Care, S.J. Parker, B.S. Zuckerman (Eds.). Boston, Ma: Little, Brown And Company, Chapter 68 (1994) (Box 4)
    - Tourette Syndrome: A Multigenerational, Neuropsychiatric Disorder. In: Behavioral Neurology Of Movement Disorders: Advances In Neurology, Volume 65. W. Weiner, A. Lang (Eds.). New York: Raven Press (1995) (Box 4)
    - Perspectives On Developmental Psychopathology. In: Developmental Psychopathology: Theory And Method, Vol. 1., Chapter 1. D. Cicchetti, D.J. Cohen (Eds.). New York: John Wiley and Sons, Inc. (1995) (Box 4)
    - Inner Lives Of Individuals And Families Living With Tourette's Syndrome. In: Movement And Allied Disorders. M.M. Robertson, V. Eapen (Eds.). London: John Wiley and Sons, Inc., Chapter 3 (1995). Proof and some correspondence (Box 4)
    - Tic Disorders. In: Treatments Of Psychiatric Disorders, Second Edition. G. Clabbard (Ed.). Washington, Dc: Apa Press, Chapter 10 (1996) (Box 4)
    - Issues For Research. In: Psychoses And Pervasive Developmental Disorders In Childhood And Adolescence. F.R. Volkmar (Ed.). Washington, Dc: American Psychiatric Press, Inc., Chapter 9 (1996) (Box 4)
    - Perspectives Theoriques Sur L'autism. Psychiatrie De L'enfant, XXXVIII, 2, Pp (1996) (Box 4)
    - Neurobiology Of Neuropsychiatric Disorders. In: Child And Adolescent Psychiatry: A Comprehensive Textbook, Second Edition. M. Lewis, (Ed.). Baltimore: Williams and Wilkins, Chapter 3 (1996) (Box 4)
    - Foreword. In: Children In Jeopardy: Can We Break The Cycle Of Poverty? I. Harris (Ed.). New Haven: Yale Child Study Center/Yale University Press (1996) (Box 4)
    - Foreword. In: Rallying The Whole Village: The Comer Process For School Development. J. Comer, N. Haynes, E. Joyner, M. Ben-Avie (Eds.). New York: Teachers College Press, Columbia University, Pp (1996) (Box 4)
    - Child Development And Their Adaptation To Catastrophic Circumstances. In: Minefields In Their Hearts: The Mental Health Of Children In War And Communal Violence. R.J. Apfel and B. Simon (Eds.). New Haven: Yale University Press, Chapter 6 (1996) (Box 4)
    - Biologic Procedures: Ethical Issues In Research With Children And Adolescents. In: Ethical Isues In Mental Health Research With Children And Adolescents. K. Hoagwood, P.S. Jensen, Celia B. Fisher (Eds.). New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Chapter 7 (1996) (Box 4)
    - The Pervasive Developmental Disorders: Diagnosis And Assessment. In: Psychiatric Clinics Of North America, F.R. Volkmar (Ed.), Vol.5, Num. 4 (1996) (Box 4)
    - Language And Speech Disorders. In: Dsm-Iv Sourcebook, T.A. Widiger, A.J. Frances, H.A. Pincus, R.Ross. M.B. First, W. Davis (Eds.). Washington, D.C.: American Psychiatric Press, Chapter 7 (1997) (Box 4)
    - Childhood Disintegrative Disorder. In: Handbook Of Autism And Pervasive Developmental Disorders, Second Edition, D.J. Co Hen, F.R. Volkmar (Eds.). New York: John Wiley and Sons, Inc (1996) (Box 4)
    - Research In Child And Adolescent Psychiatry. In: Textbook Of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, S. Tyano, A. Apter, A. Weizman, J. Hattab (Eds.). Tel Aviv, Israel (1997) (Box 4)
    - Developmental Psychopathology And Child Mental Health Services: Risk And Protective Factors In Children, Families, And Society. In: Young, J.G. And Ferrari, P. (Eds.) Designing Mental Health Services And Systems For Children And Adolescents, A Shrewd Investment. (1998) (Box 4)
    - Neurochemical And Neuropeptide Systems. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder, Anxiety, And Depression.. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Psychosocial And Behavioral Treatments. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons. (1999) (Box 4)
    - Evolving Models Of Pathogenesis. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, DJ, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Beyond The Diagnosis-Darwinian Perspectives On Pathways To Successful Adaptation. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Tics And Tic Disorders. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons. (1999) (Box 4)
    - Yale Approach To Assessment And Treatment. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Neuroanatomical Circuitry. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (Box 4)
    - Neurochemical And Neuropeptide Systems.. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Environmental Risk And Protective Factors.. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Differential Diagnosis. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1998) (Box 4)
    - The ‘Nonautistic' Pervasive Developmental Disorders. In: CE Coffey And Ra Brumbck (EDS) Textbook Of Pediatric Neuropsychiatry. Washington, Dc: American Psychiatric Press (1999) (Box 4)
    - Epidemiological Studies. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons. (1999) (Box 4)
    - Peer Acceptance And Adaptive Functioning. In: Leckman, Jf And Cohen, Dj, Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York: John Wiley And Sons (1999) (Box 4)
    - Theory Of Mind In Action: Developmental Perspectives On Social Neuroscience. In: Baron-Cohen, S., Tager-Flusberg, H., And Cohen, D.J. (Eds.), Understanding Other Minds, Second Edition. 15 (Box 4)
    - Introduction: The Self Under Siege. In: Leckman, J.F. And Cohen, D.J., Tourettes Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology And Clinical Care. New York, New York (1999) (Box 4)
    - Tics: When Habit-Forming Neural Systems Form Habits Of Their Own. In: Charles A. Nelson And Monica Luciana (EDS) Handbook Of Developmental Cognitive Neuroscience. London, England: MIT Press (2001) (Box 4)
  - Assorted manuscripts, articles, chapters, reviews, etc.
    - Serotonin In Hyman Lumbar Cerebrospinal Fluid (1989) (Box 5)
    - Review of Child Psychology, H. W. Stevenson (ED) (Box 5)
    - The Relationship of Attention Deficit Disorder and Tourette Syndrome (Letter to the Editor), Arch. Gen. Psychiatry Vol. 44 Nov. 1987. (Box 5)
    - The Presentation of Tourette Syndrome in a Pediatric Neurologist's Private Practice. Martin Kreminitzer, M.D., Sharon I. Ort, R.N., M.P.H., Donald J. Cohen, M.D. (Box 5)
    - Preface (Tourettes Syndrome and TIC Disorder: Clinical Understanding.) (Box 5)
    - Preface: Autism and Pervasive Development Disorders (Box 5)
    - Preadolescent Development: Case Studies in Twins. Richard A. Frank, M.D. and Donald J. Cohen, M.D. (1980) (Box 5)
    - A Possible Genetic Relationship Exists Between Tourette's Syndrome and Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (Box 5)
    - A Physician's Guide to Diagnosis and Treatment of Tourette Syndrome---A Neurological Multiple Tic Disorder. (Box 5)
    - Pharmacotheraphy of Tourette's (Box 5)
    - Syndrome and Associated Disorders (Box 5)
    - Noradrenergic and Adrenergic Functioning in Autism (Box 5)
    - Nongenetic Factors in Gilles de la Tourette's Syndrome (Box 5)
    - Neurobiological Perspectives On Neuropsychiatric Disorders Of Childhood. (Box 5)
    - Methylphenidate Treatment of Attention Deficit Disorder With Hyperactivity in Boys with Tourette Syndrome. (Some Correspondence/Letters). (Box 5)
    - Meeting Adolescent Needs (View Point) Children Today, March April 1973 (Box 5)
    - Letters to the Editor. Invasion Research and Ethics. (Box 5)
    - An Introduction to the Debate. Helen Tager-Flushberg, simon Baron-Cohen and Donald Cohen. (Box 5)
    - International year of the Child. Child Advocacy 1979 (Box 5)
    - Handbook of Autism: Reviews (Box 5)
    - Guide to the Diagnosis and Treatment of Tourette syndrome. (Box 5)
    - The Future of the Science of Psychiatry (Report of the Science Work Group of the Future of Psychiatry). (Box 5)
    - Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 3rdEd. Vol. 8 Jap Journal. (Box 5)
    - Desordres du development et de l'habitude Syndrome de La Tourette et autres tics. (Some letters/Correspondence) (Box 5)
    - Debate and Argument: The Utility of the Term Pervasive Development Disorder, Volkmar, Cohen. (1991) (Box 5)
    - Communication Development and its Disorders: A Psycholinguistic Perspective. (Box 5)
    - Cognitive and Emotional Functioning in Hypopituitary Short-Statured Children. (Box 5)
    - Clinical Research in Child Psychiatry-Methods and Strategies. (Box 5)
    - The Child's Emerging Understanding of Other Minds (1993) (Box 5)
    - Child and Adolescent Mental Health: Neurobiological and Social Knowledge and their Application for Children and Families. (1989) (Box 5)
    - Cerebrospinal Fluid Indoleamine and Monomine Effects of Fenfluramine Treatment of Infantile Autism. (1985) (Box 5)
    - Catecholamine-Thyroid Hormone Interactions II: Thyroid Hormone and Platelet MAO Activity in Patients with Thyroid Disorders (1982) (Box 5)
    - Catecholamine-Thyroid Hormone Interactions II: Thyroid Hormone and Platelet MAO Activity in Psychiatrically Disturbed Children (1982) (Box 5)
    - Catecholamine Metabolites in Tourette's Syndrome + Obsessive Compulsive Disorder: Debrisoquin Method (1986) (Box 5)
    - The Care of Eczema: An Outline for Parents. (Box 5)
    - Bibliography in Child Psychiatry. (One page with Correspondence) 1988. (Box 5)
    - Attentional and Perceptual Measures: Developmental Changes (Box 5)
    - Attentional and Perceptual disturbances in Children With Tourette's Syndrome, Attention Deficit Disorder, and Epilepsy. (Box 5)
    - A Manual for Assessment of Clinical Adaptive Functioning of Provider Systems: The Clinical Assessment Conference. (Box 5)
    - Assessment of Brain Function in Clinical Pediatric Research: Behavioral and Biological Strategies. (Box 5)
    - Assessment of Brain Function in Clinical Pediatric Research: Behavioral and Biological Strategies. (Box 5)
    - Adaptive Behavioral Outcome in Adolescents With Developmental Language Disorders. (Box 5)
    - Youth as Advocates. Children Today (1972). (Box 5)
    - Yale-Paris Other Injurious Behavior Scale (YAPA-OIB) (Box 5)
    - The Use of "Asperger's Syndrome". (1985) (Box 5)
    - Basal Ganglia Research and Tourette's Syndrome. Letters to the Editor. (Box 5)
    - Thyroid Function in Developmental Disorders. (Box 5)
    - Tourette Syndrome and Neuropsychiatric Disorders: Is There a Genetic Relationship? Letters to the Editor. (Box 5)
    - The Therapeutic Effect of Clonidine in Attention Deficit Disorder With Hyperactivity: A Comparison With Placebo and Methylphenidate. (1986) (Box 5)
    - Proposal Letter to "Discovery Health Media". (1999). (Box 5)
    - Tourette's Syndrome: Developmental Psychopathology of a Model Neuropsychiatric Disorder of Childhood. (Streker Monograph Series 1990). (Box 5)
    - Into Life: Autism, Tourette's Syndrome and the Community of Clinical Research. (2001) (Box 5)
    - Multiplex Developmental Disorder (French Paper) (Box 5)
    - Presentation of a Diagnostic Grid of the Progressive Stages of Infantile Autism as Observed in Treatment. (1998) with corrections and some correspondence. (Box 5)
    - Study of the Relationship Between Self-Injurious Behavior and Plain Reactivity in Infantile Autism. (Box 5)
    - Theoretical Perspectives on Autism, Ami Klin and Donald J. Cohen (Box 5)
    - Strategies for Study of the Neurochemistry of Attention Deficit Disorder in Children (Box 5)
    - Stimulant Medications in Tourette Syndrome. Letter to the Editor. (Box 5)
    - Some Relation of Parental Attitudes to the Development of Identical Twins: Case Reports. (Box 5)
    - Silent Victims. Children who Witness Violence. (Commentary) (Box 5)
    - Sick Man Surrounded by Physicians, Saints, And Demons. (Box 5)
    - Speech and Prosody Characteristics of Adolescents and Adults With High Functioning Autism and Asperger Syndrome. (Box 5)
    - Correspondence regarding "Understanding Other Minds". Oxford University Press. of Chapter 15.with hand corrections "Theory of Mind in Action: Developmental Perspectives on Social Neuroscience. (Box 5)
    - A Note on Nosology. (1999) Includes a Floppy. (Box 5)
    - Guanfacine in the Treatment of Children with Tic Disorders and ADHD. A Placebo-Controlled Study. (2000) (Box 5)
    - Adolescent Depression: Window of (Missed?) Opportunity. (with Correspondence) (Box 5)
    - Social Brain (with title suggestion from Ami) (Box 5)
    - Grammatical and Pragmatic Prosody in High Functioning Individuals with Autism: A Pilot Study. (Poster presentation 2000 Symposium for Research in Child Language Disorders, Madison, WI.) (Box 5)
    - Running Title: The Mother-Child Dyad Facing Trauma (Some Correspondence) (Box 5)
    - Healing Children's Grief: Surviving a Parent's Death From Cancer (Box 5)
    - Tourette's Syndrome-Tics, Obsessions, Compulsions: Developmental Psychopathology and Clinical Care (1999). (Box 5)
    - Neuropsychiatric Disorders of Childhood: Tourette's Syndrome as a model. (Box 5)
    - Chapter 19: Developmentally Based Assessments. (Box 5)
    - Tourette's Syndrome (1999) (Box 5)
    - Stimulant Medications in Tourette's Syndrome (Box 5)
    - A Normed Study of Face Recognition in Autism and Related Disorders. (Box 5)
    - Tourette Syndrome Diagnostic Confidence Index: Development and Clinical Associations. Final Paper (Box 5)
    - The Gilles De La Tourette Syndrome Diagnostic Confidence Index: Development, Acceptability and Association with Clinical Factors (Box 5)
    - Address to the Students of New Haven on "Violence". (Box 5)
    - Police and Mental Health Professionals. (Box 5)
    - The Treatment of Tourette's Syndrome: Multimodel, Developmental Intervention. (Box 5)
    - A Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Study of Risperidone in Adults with Autistic Disorder and Other Pervasive Developmental Disorders. (Box 5)
    - Early Parental Preoccupations and Behavior and Their Possible Relationship to the Symptoms of Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder. (Box 5)
    - Developmental Psychopathology: A Framework for Planning Child Mental Health. (Box 5)
    - Multiplex Developmental Disorders: The Role of Communication in the Construction of a Self. (Box 5)
    - Autism And Related Conditions: A Status Report. (Box 5)
    - Handbook of Autism and Pervasive Developmental Disorders (A Review of the Handbook from Korea) (Box 5)
    - Handbook of Autism and Pervasive Developmental Disorders (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 5)
    - Senn Conference Room Proposal (Architectural Diagrams) (Box 5)
    - A Proposal for A New Department of Child Health (Includes Correspondence) (Box 5)
    - Proposal for the establishment of The Department of Child Psychiatry In The Yale-New Haven Hospital (Includes Correspondence) (Box 5)
    - Child Study Center, Yale University School Of Medicine. (Annual Report 1998-99) (Box 5)
    - Accomplishment of the Yale Child Study Center (Photocopies of Slides Presentation) (Box 5)
    - Child Study, FY 96 Planning Meeting with Deputy Deans. Background Information Package. (March 29, 1996) (Box 5)
    - Child Study, Planning Meeting with Deputy Deans. Background Information Package. (November 25, 1996) (Box 5)
    - Yale Guide to Understanding your Child (1stand 2ndRevision of the Book) (Box 5)
    - Yale Companion for Parents: Understanding Your Child and You. (Draft of the Book) (Box 6)
    - Can They Hope to Feel Safe Again: The Impact of Community Violence in Infants, Toddlers, their parents and practitioners. (1991) (Box 6)
    - The Yale Guide to Your Child's Behavior and Development. (Related Correspondence Included) (Box 6)
  - Audio-visual materials
    - Polaroid Camera used by Dr. Cohen (Box 7)
    - Loose Photographs and Black and White Photographs of Children (Box 8)
    - 35 mm Slides of different lectures (Box 10–13)
    - Glass/Plastic Slides (Large) of various lectures of Dr. Cohen (Original Metal Box) (Box 14)
  - Audiorecordings
    - Tourette Syndrome, 2 audiotapes, 1981 May 27 (Box 15)
    - Closing Plenary Session "Child Psychiatrist at Front" AACAP Annual Meeting, 2 audiotapes, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Commission on Children, 1990; 1 (Box 15)
    - IACAPP 13th International Congress, 5 audiotapes, 1994 (Box 15)
    - 92 APA-PS2A, New Findings and Old Truths in Child Psychiatry Part I (1992 APA Washington DC.), 1 (Box 15)
    - AACAP 38th Annual Meeting, 1991; 1 (Box 15)
    - Memorial Gathering "Sally A. Provence M.D," 2 audiotapes (Box 15)
    - Memorial Gathering "Lottie Newman," 3 audiotapes (Box 15)
    - Zero to Three. Speech of the First Lady "Hillary Rodham Clinton," at Dolly Madison Award to Sally Provence M.D., 11 audiotapes, 1993 December 4 (Box 15)
    - Zero to Three. Speech of the First Lady "Hillary Rodham Clinton," at Dolly Madison Award to Sally Provence M.D., 2 audiotapes, 1993 December 4 (Box 15)
  - Graphs/Charts of different studies/lectures (Box 16)
  - Toys made by different children (Box 17)
  - Negatives (Box 17)
  - Brain Sections (Small Box) (Box 17)
  - Films
    - Unstructured Mannerism, film reel (16mm) (Box 17)
    - Basketball, film reel (16mm) (Box 17)
    - General Coordination Behavior, film reel (16mm) (Box 17)
    - Social, film reel (16mm) (Box 17)
- Records of Donald J. Cohen as director, circa 1983-2001; Accession 2003-A-024
  - Anti Defamation League (Collaboration/Brochure) Lisa Bigman (Box 1)
  - Armenian Psychiatrist/Psychologist (Box 1)
  - Attention Deficit Disorder (Box 1)
  - A Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 1)
  - American Journal of Psychiatry (Editorial Board Meeting, Agenda Jan 28, 2000) (Box 1)
  - ACP (American College of Psychoanalysts) (Box 1)
  - Accreditation (CSC) (Box 1)
  - Accreditation Council for Services for Mentally Retarded and other Developmentally Disabled Persons (AC MRDD) (Box 1)
  - ACES Meeting (March 6, 1985, Mill Rock School) (Box 1)
  - Accreditation Council Site Visit- Psych. Residents, October 8, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica, Leckman, Mays, et al. (Box 1)
  - Administrative Guidelines Medical Staff, Child Study Center Case Manual and Description (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee for Parenting Education List of Members (Box 1)
  - All Our Kin (Box 1)
  - Alto Bello (Meriden, Connecticut, April 24, 1985). (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Child Psychiatry (Committee on Research/Biological Aspects of Child Psychiatry) (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry: Work Group On Research. (Box 1)
  - American Board of Psychiatry and Neurology (Box 1)
  - American College of Neuropharmacology (Box 1)
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee (Chana Katz, David Epstein, Talal Dolev September 14, 1992 visit) (Box 1)
  - American Psychiatric Association (Box 1)
  - American Psychiatric Institute for Research and Education (Regier, Darrel A.) (Box 1)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association Membership (Box 1)
  - American Psychological Association (Site Visit 12/12/83) and Publication Manual (Box 1)
  - American Academy (Forum on Psychoactive Medications at AACAP meeting. (Box 1)
  - American Public Welfare Association (Box 1)
  - Amistad Academy (Box 1)
  - Anna Freud Center (Box 1)
  - Anna Freud Center Meeting Nov 1-2, 1996, Correspondence and Financial Statements (Box 1)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'Nai B'Rith (Box 2)
  - Arcon (Box 2)
  - ASAP (Adolescent Substance Abuse Prevention Program) (Box 2)
  - ASAP/CATCH Project (Box 2)
  - Autistic Disorder Criteria (Box 2)
  - Autism Society of America Scientific Advisory Board (Box 2)
  - Autism Society of America: Use of Aversive (Box 2)
  - Governor's Committee on Autism (Box 2)
  - Bancroft Newshealth (Box 2)
  - Bar-Ilan University (Box 3)
  - Bar-Ner Uri (Children Medical Center of Israel) (Box 3)
  - Behavior Research Institute (Box 3)
  - Benhaven School; Also Corresspondence with Amy Lattick and Larry Wood. (Box 3)
  - Benhaven Course (Box 3)
  - Benhaven Lifetime Agreement (Box 3)
  - Benhaven Search Committee (Box 3)
  - Benhaven: Human Investigation Committee (Box 3)